Nicole: We can see that threats to
organisations can come from a range of
sources external and internal, ‘threat
actors’ may even attack home workers
or users via a phishing email, text,
phone call, or by using cleverly worded
messages on other communication systems
such as Slack or Microsoft Teams.
This can then make them become the
'threat actor' unintentionally,
therefore everyone should be aware of
the importance of safeguarding their
data and protecting their devices.
So, what are some of the
motives for external threats
One of the most common motives for
external threats is for financial gain
by getting access to customers financial
details such as credit or debit card data.
They also can access email addresses
and login credentials gaining access
to a great many personal computers
and subsequently more financial gain.
Bank details can be used to
access bank accounts and misdirect
individuals into believing they are
being contacted by their own banks.
By using ransomware external threat
actors can also hold a company to ransom
and affect its security credibility.
They can also impact a company's
profitability as they may
not be able to function.
This can make it easier for other
businesses to take their place.
Now let’s look at motives
for insider threats.
Financial gain can also be a
motive for insider threats where
unscrupulous employees may access
customers financial details, data and
databases and sell them on to others.
They may also want to act maliciously
passing on secrets or information to
other companies or organisations for
financial gain or to undermine a company.
It’s also becoming increasingly common
for cybercriminals to try to “recruit”
people working inside companies, who
have privileged access to systems.
They get them to share their access and
in return they get a cut of the profits.